Are you in or out?
Ocean's Eleven is a thriller, crime film directed by Steven Soderbergh.
Less than 24 hours into his parole, charismatic thief Danny Ocean is already rolling out his next plan: In one night, Danny's
hand-picked crew of specialists will attempt to steal more than $150 million from three Las Vegas casinos.
But to score the cash, Danny risks his chances of
reconciling with ex-wife, Tess.
Danny Ocean, played by George Clooney.
Rusty Ryan, played by Brad Pitt.
Terry Benedict, played by Andy Garcia.
Linus Caldwell, played by Matt Damon.
Tess Ocean, played by Julia Roberts.
Virgil Malloy, played by Casey Affleck.
Ocean's Eleven is a 2001 American heist comedy film directed by
Steven Soderbergh from a screenplay by Ted Griffin.
The first installment in the Ocean's film trilogy, it
is a remake of the 1960 Rat Pack film.
The film features an ensemble cast including George Clooney, Matt Damon, Andy García, Brad Pitt, Julia
Roberts, Casey Affleck, Don Cheadle, Scott Caan, Elliott Gould, Bernie Mac and Carl Reiner.
The story follows friends Danny Ocean (Clooney) and Rusty Ryan (Pitt), who plan a heist of $160 million
from casino owner Terry Benedict (García), the lover of Ocean's ex-wife Tess (Roberts).
Ocean's Eleven was theatrically released in the United
States on December 7, 2001, by Warner Bros.
The film received positive reviews from critics and was a major box-office hit, grossing
$450.7 million worldwide and becoming the fifth-highest-grossing film of 2001.
Soderbergh directed two sequels, Ocean's Twelve in
2004 and Ocean's Thirteen in 2007.
Ocean's 8, a spin-off with an all-female lead cast, was released in 2018.
The film explores themes of casino, pickpocket, heist, con artist, remake.
The tone is intense.